## BEN CAMPANARO visual effects compositor

### profile

I'm an Emmy-nominated visual effects compositor, an "in-the-trenches" department supervisor, and a goal-focused project manager with proven success on television, commercial, and feature film projects. I've also enjoyed active roles in concept development, on-set supervision, title design, motion graphics, and marketing. I excel in a fast-paced environment, and specialize in developing new techniques to efficiently solve the most daunting visual effects challenges.

## experience

Please see attached filmography...

VFX Supervisor / Compositing Supervisor, Origin Digital Studios Burbank, CA

Mar 2014 - Present

- Oversaw a team ranging from 3-15 artists as a founding member of a new television VFX studio
- Partnered with Management, Producers, and TDs to establish the protocols and pipeline for the facility
- Composited hero shots, established key looks and treatments, and designed templates to maintain scene continuity
- Balanced crew assignments with individual skillsets and deadlines across simultaneous projects
- Reviewed artist submissions and provided technical and creative direction
- Led "dailies" screenings and Cinesync sessions with satellite offices, vendors, and clients to discuss notes
- Participated in script breakdown and bid meetings to establish goals and timelines with Producers
- Researched new software tools and compositing techniques, and trained artists on their use
- Brainstormed with Directors and VFX Supervisors to solve storytelling challenges and plan plate photography
- Interviewed and recruited artists and outsource vendors
- Oversaw company demo reels, award submission entries, and designed accompanying handouts
- Provided backup Supervision on set for VFX plate photography ("True Detective" and "Scorpion")

Contributing Writer, **Post Magazine** Hollywood, Studio City, Culver City, & Anaheim, CA and Tokyo, Japan

May 2010 - Nov 2013

- Provided live coverage and summary articles of entertainment technology conventions, award shows, summits, etc.
- Tested and reviewed pre-release and final versions of VFX software, workstations, and professional display monitors

Compositing Supervisor / Lead Compositor, **Pixomondo** Burbank, CA

Jan 2011 - May 2013

Lead Compositor, Eden FX Hollywood & Santa Monica, CA

Aug 2007 - Dec 2010

Project Manager / Digital Artist, Mechnology VFX Studio Hollywood & Burbank, CA

Mar 2005 - Aug 2007

Visual Effects Assistant (on set), "Charmed" Paramount Studios Hollywood, CA

Jul 2005 - May 2006

- Helped the VFX Supervisor oversee plate photography and completion of nearly 1,000 shots throughout the season
- Attended production meetings, wrote script breakdowns and provided backup VFX Supervision on set
- Designed and executed computer screen graphics for live playback and actor interaction

#### Freelance Multimedia Artist Thousand Oaks, CA

Jan 2004 - Dec 2008

- Co-created a documentary short with a pre-release camera and software, exhibited by Microsoft, JVC, and Adobe
- Developed a TV miniseries concept pitch and presented to the Head of Drama Development at NBC-Universal
- Produced animated sequences, titles, and interactive kiosks for live theater performances and trade conventions

#### skills

- 10+ years professional production experience as a VFX compositor, specializing in Nuke and After Effects
- Solid knowledge across the VFX pipeline, with experience including: V-Ray AOV Integration, 3D Camera Projection, Deep Data, Normals Re-Lighting, Keying/Roto, Paint, Lut/CDL Management, Color Timing, 2D/Planar/3D Tracking, 2.5D Layering, Particles, 2D Animation, Matte Painting, Cloth Simulation, Title Design, Motion Graphics, and Expressions
- Task-specific experience with Maya, Cinema 4D, and Fusion. Also proficient with Mocha, Boujou, Syntheyes, Particular, Sapphire, Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Illustrator, InDesign, Office, RV, Shotgun, and more

# BEN CAMPANARO visual effects compositor

#### education

Bachelor of Arts Degree in Multimedia, Summa Cum Laude - California Lutheran University

May 2005

## filmography (abbreviated)

### visit linkedin.com/in/bencampanaro for a full list

features:	television:	
Spring Breakers	The Walking Dead	TWC/HBO - 'Dragon' (commercial)
Mission: Impossible 4	True Detective	Mockingbird Lane
The Amazing Spider-Man	Limitless	Outsourced
The Hunger Games	Sleepy Hollow	Red Widow
The Social Network	Agent X	No Ordinary Family
Get Smart	Scorpion	Perception
Miss Nobody	South of Hell	Brothers & Sisters
Temple Grandin	Devious Maids	Ghost Whisperer
Cinema Verite	Da Vinci's Demons	Flash Forward
Nim's Island	Fringe	Burn Notice
You Kill Me	Grimm	Undercovers
Bonneville	The Mindy Project	Army Wives
Even Money	Terra Nova	Lost
The Last Word	Revolution	Pushing Daisies
The Initiation of Sarah	Community	NCIS
The Curse of King Tut's Tomb	Hawaii Five-O	Without A Trace
No Subtitles Necessary	Game of Thrones	Charmed

## press featured in:

Imagineer Systems (Mocha) Online "Artist Profile," by Ross Shain	9/2013
FXGuide's "Creature Features: VFX in TV Commercials - Dragon," by Ian Failes	4/2013
CG Society's "Production Focus / Mission: Impossible 4 - Ghost Protocol," by Trevor Hogg	2/2012
Computer Graphics World Magazine's "A Series with Bite: Terra Nova," by Courtney Howard	11/2011
FXGuide's "Dino-Sized Effects in Terra Nova," by Ian Failes	9/2011
HDRI 3D Magazine's "Ten Days: Ghost Whisperer," by Briar Lee Mitchell	6/2009
Ghost Whisperer - Season 3 DVD Featurette, "Welcome to the Underworld"	9/2008
Post Magazine's "Mechnology Provides VFX for Veronica Mars Finale," by Randi Altman	7/2006

## **awards** *primetime emmy:*

"Ghost Whisperer" - Personally nominated for Outstanding VFX in a Broadcast Program	2009
"Da Vinci's Demons" - Contributed to nominee for Outstanding VFX in a Supporting Role	2013
"Revolution" - Contributed to nominee for Outstanding VFX in a Supporting Role	2013
"Game of Thrones" - Contributed to winner for Outstanding VFX in a Broadcast Program	2012

#### ves awards:

"Da Vinci's Demons" - Contributed to nominee for Outstanding VFX in a Broadcast Program	2014
"Game of Thrones" - Contributed to winner for Outstanding VFX in a Broadcast Program	2013
"Mockingbird Lane" - Contributed to nominee for Outstanding VFX in a Broadcast Program	2013
"Terra Nova" - Contributed to winner for Outstanding VFX in a Broadcast Program	2012
"Terra Nova" - Contributed to nominee for Created Environment in a Broadcast Program	2012
"Ghost Whisperer" - Contributed to nominee for Outstanding VFX in a Broadcast Program	2012